Maxim Danilov

J + 43(681)207-44-776 $rac{1}{2}$ maxim@wpshop.at

Languages: conversational English and German, basic Italian, native Russian

SUMMARY

I am a DevRel and senior developer for the past 27 years. I have led teams, launched startups, spoken at tech conferences, write and reviewed tons of code, written articles, and contributed to open source. A complete list of my DevRel activity - gist.github.com/danilovmy/df3bec0fbe0ee264634dad98c8e3c688

Looking for positions: DevRel, Developer Advocate, Team Lead

Desired tasks and future goals: Leading development teams, become an ambassador of a technology or product, mentoring teams, speaking at conferences, writing articles and working with the community.

EDUCATION

Moscow Power Engineering Institute - Master's degree in Electronics and Microelectronics.

Institute of Psychology and Social Work - Child Preschool Psychologist.

Erickson Coaching International - Mental Coach in Management.

SKILLS AND EXPERIENCE

- Software development, 27 years.
- SQL/No-SQL Databases 25 years, Pyton/Django 9 years, VueJs/NuxtJs 5 years.
- Public speaking to large audiences in three languages, 28 years.
- Speaker on Tech conferences since 2019. Author of Articles since 2004.
- Tech Mentoring and Code Coaching, 27 years of work with students, mentees, employee.
- **Team Leadership** 7 years of experience.

Additional skills: DRF, Django-Admin, GeoDjango, FastAPI, Pydantic, Deno.Fresh, ReportLab, JavaScript, able to work in startup environment, able to work on camera, can be very convincing.

Working experience

Mentor in Engineering, consultant on ADPList, 2023-now

Contributed in open-source projects of python ecosystem, write articles, contribute to python community mission to provide tech mentorship for every community member. Twice got the "SuperMentor" award.

Consultant, Senior Python Developer, 2023-2024, 0.5 years

Resolved architectural issues in Python projects and in Python's ecosystem. Mentoring for engineers.

Owner, CTO, Tech Lead, Software Architect in wP soft GmbH 2020-2023, 3 years

Develop python-based web solutions and micro-services per demand. Work with ecosystem of Python.

- Created from scratch an e-commerce platform and high-load PDF generation service as SaaS.
- Mantainer of open-source Python/Django translation library: Django-TOF2.
- Built a developing team: 3 developers, designer and intern and provided programming mentorship.
- Spoke at Python/Django/OSS conferences and networked with developers.

Co-owner, Senior Software Developer, Software Architect in winePad.at 2015-2020, 6 years Built a biggest tech database about Alcohol in Europe. Working with old legacy ecosystem of Python.

- Developed wine Pad. at from scratch to a successful matured project with over 800k lines of code.
- Organized recruitment process, create support-team and provided programming mentorship.
- Contributed in Django project, spoken on Python/Django conferences.

Co-owner, CEO in Alpinbus GmbH, 2014-2016, 2 years. Created a network of 30 bus drivers. Co-owner, CTO in linguaXtrem GmbH, 2010-2013, 4 years. Interacted at sport conferences. CEO in Extra-service, 2006-2009, 3 years. Trained insurance salespeople (around 5000 persons). Technician in Siemens Laboratory, 1997-2006, 9 years. Teaching microelectronics to students.